[Music]
you're listening to the AI native Dev
brought to you by
[Music]
Tesla hello everyone welcome back to the
AI native Dev podcast today I have a
great guest that I actually had a chance
to go on his podcast his and Aisha's
about so six months ago I think the
episode came out a bit more recently and
that is Caleb SEMA here to talk to me
about AI security Caleb thanks for
coming on to the show ah I'm happy to be
there I'm glad you asked me that's
always fun to to chat with you we have a
good time I think they're always fun
conversations Caleb but you have an
illustrious background on it just to
give people like a quick summary on it
you founded spy Dynamics which is one of
the early players in the absc domain and
we have a bit of an interesting touch
point there on the history were
competitors there for a while yeah it's
fun times right guy and myself were it
was sanctum watchfire versus spy
Dynamics and just for the record I like
to said I believe we won that
war and we and and and just to say we
let you believe that the guy ended up
creating sneak so ultimately winning
himself I think I think it's all good
and the absc market has grown and you've
gone on to do all sorts of other great
things notably you siso at statea bricks
and at Robin Hood and you've now moved
over to a different Dark Side maybe not
the vendor but the the investor side
with white rabbit but specifically
you've been over the last little while
digging a lot into all sorts of security
topics but AI security specifically and
you have your AI security podcast that
you run with aish correct that's right
yeah so all sorts of like depth on it
and let me start off by just asking you
the simple question of it so is AI
generated code
secure yeah very broad easy question um
but I think if you just look at this
from a a very simple practical way which
is AI is created off of the most common
things that we do so the data that it's
trained on is clearly going to be
trained on what we've written as code
and how we produce code so by default I
guess the real question to ask is do we
as humans produce secure code by and
large and I think that answer based off
the success of your company got
the answer is no we do not so does AI
produce insecure code of course
absolutely it's going to produce
insecure code because that's what we
mostly produce is insecure code now I
think the bigger question though is just
because it does produce insecure code
does it mean that we can't train it to
produce secure code and if we do that
going into a little bit more philosophy
does that mean if more and more of our
code is a generated can we then make it
consistently more secure because that's
the one thing that AI can be good at is
to be have some consistency in
generating it if we teach it the right
things yeah and I think the there's an
interesting separation between whether
AI generate secure code and systems that
are AI powered generate secure code
because I think there's no serious AI
powered system that is literally just
pass the code over to the llm and then
just use whatever it is that comes out
and so if you using AI to generate code
you're probably doing a few things
before and a few things after that and
so that process of just the more
systemic creation of code versus the
random human you know who behaves in
different
ways I guess that allows you to
introduce security testing and response
to security testing as part of that
process uh and I think that's separate
to the question of whether the LMS
themselves would spit out secure code up
front yeah to is it is what you're
saying which is hey you have to not like
what's great about an LM is it's it can
be included in a systemic process that
can be automated and therefore what you
hand over to an llm can be prepped
prompt and in the right ways so that you
can ensure that at least a high
likelihood that it will produce secure
code and you can also assess after the
fact that you can confirm and assure
that it did produce at least what you
believe to be secure code and that can
then be copied and pasted thousands of
times allowing you to generate what you
really
want and I guess I was more thinking
about the latter which is you have a
repeatable way to generate code and so
you address a different problem of a
developer potentially which is they
forgot or they were too lazy or they
were not equipped to run a security test
and respond to whatever it is that the
findings were as opposed to maybe the
initial do they even know enough and did
they think enough to be able to write
secure code
AI may or may not be better at that but
either way the systems an automated
system can do the ladder more often my
ideal environment is that and I I've
said this for years I don't believe
engineers and software developers in
general should have to worry or think
about security from that perspective at
the end of the day I want the person to
say this is the functionality I want to
build I want to build a web application
that accepts this input produces this
kind of output this is what I need it to
be built and AI is going to generate the
building blocks and the code to be able
to put that web application together and
by default it should have the secure
ways of doing that so that the engineer
doesn't have to worry about it and I do
think that it's possible right I think
it's very possible to be able to get
there with yeah yeah I agree and
definitely my I think we share our view
that's the approach that any modern
application security product security
team should be embracing is to build
that type of platform yeah I think on
the point though of the llm itself
spitting out secure codes to begin with
and the training I guess one of the
challenges is that there's a a world of
code out there that the llms have been
training on and Jason Warner was on the
podcast and he pointed out that the
Dirty Little Secret is they all have the
same data they're all really training on
roughly the same set of data and that
code is substantially insecure or rather
far from perfect shall we say yeah and
then there's those that train on
Enterprise code and there we have a
different problem which is that
Enterprise code is also shall we say far
from perfect and has all sorts of
historical Legacy omissions written by
humans and so we have existing bodies of
data to train
with that are insecure or rather
that shouldn't guide the AI into into
achieving secure code right so maybe
like the question in my mind is where
would I go to if I wanted to to train AI
on secure code let's accept the theory
that if it was trained on secure code it
would just tend to generate that at
least at a higher perspective which on
on its surface feels right but I don't
know is there a body a significant body
of code on secure code that is that is
secure let's look at let's look at this
maybe very simplistically which is okay
90% of the issues that most Enterprises
worry about from a security perspective
and guy you're the expert so you correct
me on this by the way but is pretty
standard stuff right this is SQL
injection cross-site scripting buffer
overflows missing authentication not
checking for identity there's a whole
bunch of these sort of like how do I
door protection there's there's these
basic fundamental things that in reality
is 90% plus of the issues in what we
would call insecure code right right and
so then secure code quote unquote would
be the ones that don't have those issues
or have clearly inserted protective
methods for these kinds of issues
and so here's the thing about llms is
not only yes the majority of the time by
and large the most predictable is
insecure code however it absolutely has
all the knowledge of those secure ways
too right you just have to direct it
towards that area so as opposed to for
example I bet if you said create a web
application that accepts input sticks it
into a SQL database and that was it and
you ran that a 100 times how many of
those 100 results would include just a
straight up SQL injectable query is I
mean I haven't done this test but I
would say by and large probably on a
generic LL Model A lot of models may
have changed this but it's probably
pretty high like it'll have SQL
injectable code in there if you say hey
I want you to write a safe secure
reliable web application that takes
input puts it into a SQL database it
would be interesting to see what the
result of that is is whether that
percentage would change would it write a
more safe and secure and not just do ad
hoc SQL injection to a SQL database uh
my my belief and at least in the test
that we have done again is not my job
but just in general around certain
things that I've run into it does write
actual safe code and in fact I know that
in Robin Hood when llms first came out
the head of our appc team at the time
ran a Fest was is basically let's just
run a week let's build something useful
out of nlm and of course the first thing
that appet guys are going to do is can
we produce remediation for these
vulnerabilities and in one week a pretty
decent small team there was able to with
very high accuracy and reliability
produce real solutions to these problems
automatically identified by sneak it was
like oh here's the sneak item let's take
it let's prompt it let's shove it to
write me a safe reliable version of this
and it does fairly accurately with very
high reliability produce the right bit
of code that then can just be committed
as a PR I think it's just about how you
change the prompt and how you define
what you really want that it absolutely
can produce the right thing if you want
it to yeah I think I find it exciting
and at the same time feels sometimes a
little bit like self-driving cars which
is close to what we want but has been
for for a long time and there's like a
leap of faith and I think a part of that
is the distance between the the
anecdotal examples right like the the
cases where yeah I I ran it I generate
it a bunch of times and it often did and
some form of predictability or trust and
I guess the question is if you're an
absc person and you need to also you
know comply with all sorts of things but
let's let's focus on actual wanting
secure
systems so if you want your system to be
secure are you comfortable running uh a
scanner or rather generating code which
let's assume it has the same knowledge
when it generates code for it to to know
whether that code is secure that's about
the same level of knowledge as if you
gave it code and you asked it is this
code secure so let's assume you can
prompt it in both cases in the optimal
case to extract the ability are you
comfortable with a situation in which
you're running that scanner and the same
scanner on the same code let's say eight
times out of 10 nine times out of 10
will find a vulnerability and the 10th
time same scanner on same code will not
find it and also maybe that one time out
of 10 make up one but I think we're
fairly familiar with false positives so
I think that bothers me a little bit
less it's a great you're what you're
really asking for is given me
consistency where where is it that my
risk
tolerance of a system says it's okay to
miss a vulner ility right is really what
you're asking and and inconsistently and
so it's not about missing aity it's
about I scanned this Cons with this tool
and it found a vulnerability and then
the next day I scan it and it does not
find the vulnerability and I think the
vulnerability went
away yeah so obviously the answer for
most people I think would be that is
unacceptable right like you need to have
consistency to say if I scan something
and you find it you need to find it what
I find though in the real world
especially in this llm sort of world is
there are there's gives and takes
benefits and PS where okay let me
rephrase your question back to you which
is okay let's say eight times out of 10
I find the correct vulnerability but
there is a this 20% chance at which it
just does not flag but that by itself is
unacceptable however if I let's say that
is true but I'll also produce let's just
say 80% less false positives for you is
that then become acceptable it's an
interesting now debate to uh a security
team to say or I find 40% more things
that are true positives that you weren't
able to find with a Statics scanner oh
man like there there becomes this real
interesting world real world challenge
and and here's the answer to this right
the answer to it is I don't think
consistent static code analyzers go away
right there is a foundation that needs
to be applied so that you can get the
consistency and there is a set of logic
at least today this may go away in five
years but like at least Point yeah at
some point at least day I want to
augment this piece right I want to say I
want the consistency I want the
capability and I know what I know and I
think that is very in order to judge my
risk in order to judge my Effectiveness
in order to have consistency that is
required however if I augment on top of
that this sort of llm like capability
that gives me that either will reconfirm
with that existing static system and or
will find more that static system is
just not capable of doing then that may
be worth the benefit yeah that's I think
there was a ton of value in in the LMS
in the systems and I think it's
fascinating to think about dealing with
lack of predictability and I think
that's a general problem in the world of
llms systems are less predictable and
we're used to the machine doing the same
thing again and again consistently and
the fact that it doesn't is sometimes
puzzling sometimes highly uncomfortable
and makes it hard to make decisions it's
interesting because what would you
expect to some to some I say it's built
off of its entire goal is to mimic a
human our entire goal is to build a
human humans their power and their
failure is they are unpredictable that
is that's the benefit of an llm is it's
fuzzy and so the question that I then
Reas in the way that I'm learn and I'm
by the way I'm learning about this same
as anyone else of course we all are y
hey the way I'm starting to think about
this is uh would I ask a human to do
this and would I expect them to be able
to do this consistently and the answer
is probably no but what I could do is
possibly ask the LM to write the code or
the system to produce the system to do
this consistently and that may be
interesting and that may be the route at
which I go and then use the llm for very
specific fuzzy logic or knowledge that
needs to be created at runtime where it
is okay in fact it is expected to be
somewhat fuzzy and not consistent and
then how do I structure the system
effectively so that is the way that we
think about it yeah and and I think a
lot about trust in the context of when
do we trust humans and when do we trust
Ai and and how do we decide to doing it
data shows a lot of it comes from the
self-driving cars that there are two
types of mistakes that could happen
there are mistakes that humans might do
and AI doesn't and there are mistakes
that AI might do and humans never do and
when humans encounter those types of
mistakes they get angry they don't just
get disappointed or they just get angry
they get tricked when a self-driving car
thinks that a leaf that is in the middle
of the road is a child and would not
continue to to run they're just like oh
it's a bug in the system they get
annoyed they feel let down or something
and it feels like that how would a
developer or an absc person respond to a
system that is maybe when you look at
the statistics doing a good job finding
things with the right ratios and all
that jazz but from time to time it makes
these mistakes that just truly annoy you
because it feels stupid to you it feels
like how can it be so unintelligent that
it make those mistakes and um I guess
maybe my my my question here for your
perspective is we have all these
mechanisms around
trust with humans seniority of a
developer track record maybe within the
organization sometimes just rhetoric and
and how they speak about security but we
have these measures of choosing whether
or not to trust a security person or a
developer who has looked at the code and
said that this is secure and with AI we
lack those a little bit we're it's the
system and so we sometimes have this
expectation of perfection how how do you
think what do we need to be able to
build some measure of trust when do we
know whether that clean bill of health
that we've received is something that we
can or cannot trust as individuals
because it's the system will not give us
this predictably so we need some measure
right man that is a very
complicated question it's the things
that I that kind of pop up to my head
immediately is yeah why do we get
annoyed I guess at the first and it's
because
obviously the cause for the error
there's two there's a margin of error
and then there's the error itself right
if the margin is too large it's clearly
not there but even if the error itself
is it obvious or is it subtle right like
to your point if it's a leaf blowing in
the front of the car and it thinks it's
a child and it Slams on the brakes like
that's really bad because that actually
could cause an accident behind us for no
reason that's an obvious eror and it's
not a subtle one however if the car
slammed on its brakes for a dog running
across the street that's a subtle like
should you or should you not is it will
are you willing to run over a dog that
may in order to not cause more accidents
behind you or not is it more like a rat
or something you know yeah a rat yeah
maybe not people but there's a more
subtlety in terms of that at where then
it becomes not more annoying but it
becomes a really hard decision that may
have to be made so one I think what type
of error is a subtle or an obvious error
causes that and then the next thing
you're question about what then how does
that apply from an engineering
perspective like to your point I expect
a senior engineer to create subtle
errors not obvious errors if I'm a
junior engineer we're GNA create obvious
errors not subtle errors and so today I
think that a couple things one I don't
know from an AI perspective if we've
even really defined does AI create or
even identify the difference between
obvious or subtle errors that's a good
question I don't know if anyone's really
done any tests on those kinds of things
to really Define that I think the
obvious the piece about obvious is
tricky because the whole notion is that
this intelligence doesn't work precisely
the same way and so it's obvious to us
that it's easy to count the number of RS
in strawberry and it's hard for AI to do
that and so so it feels like this infu
these types of mistakes are the ones
that Anno be so dense that you cannot
figure this out and and as a result it
it maybe casts a doubt about can I
really trust anything else that you say
when you make these types of mistakes
yeah which I really think is I think
there's only two ways to resolve this
again in my very limited I'm just going
to I make things simple clearly there's
more than two ways but my two ways that
come to the top of my head is first I
think is time at the end of the day why
can't you trust something is because
it's new we haven't seen it perform and
deal with issues crisises problems
challenges it need there needs to be a
test of time that takes place and for
any new technology mobile Cloud all of
these things there's a test of time as
to how does it evolve how does it stand
the test of time and what level of trust
can we really put into it and for the
humans right both for the technology to
identify problems fix them get to some
plateau of capability but also for the
humans to build some form of some form
ofense trust with it yeah hey I have
trust in AWS when it first when Cloud
first came out did I no absolutely not
as everyone did and so it just takes
time and the second one is probably a
harder one but there's
accountability like with a senior
engineer there's accountability that has
to be had there is a sense of Pride job
that they have and there's there's
ramifications to not doing a great job
you get fired you you get yelled at by
your B you get whatever these things are
there's some sort of impact that occurs
and I think one of the things and we're
getting into Super philosophy around
threat to nation and people with AI but
does AI have accountability right right
isn't interesting and I think that's a
massive question and I think the answer
is pretty obviously no because there is
no entity that is AI today the companies
behind the AI there's a question there
about how accountable they are for it
and probably that type of insurance
uh issue is one of the holding back
factors for self-driving cars and others
I do to bring it back a little bit to
appsc code security I do wonder whether
there's a bit of an outsides implication
to this when you talk about risk
reduction in code because to begin with
it's something that is invisible right
security is invisible we don't know if
the AI misses something and so we lose
if if it if we asked it a math question
and it gave us an incorrect result then
from time to time we will notice that if
we try spw broke it didn't compile see
it might get annoyed might get whatever
but we would know that it occurred
versus when it missed issues and so it's
interesting on one hand super compelling
I'm super excited by the ability of llms
to both generate fixes of
vulnerabilities to identify issues to
generate code that I do think over time
can be trained to be more secure at the
same time how do we
know as long as it's not predictable who
is it that would identify whether a
mistake occurred and and the other
question to ask here is what's our
expectation is our expectation 100% % I
don't think that's I don't think that's
viable and I just think that's not
realistic just look at secure code if we
can make a 10% dent in better code
through isn't that worth it that's worth
it right there's when you think about
risk management and when you think about
and here's the thing is I think we as
security people myself included I'm
guilty of this is we tend to always
point out the 1% right if it's not
perfect if it doesn't fit this thing
then clearly that's like our job is to
poke holes and things but ultimately if
it gets us in a better place um and
security or security of code in general
is better by 10% that's worth it you can
miss a couple that's okay we've improved
by another 10% and we've we've resolved
300 more that we never would have gotten
and so I feel like that's a risk worth
taking yeah I I agree and I think maybe
the flip side of that is if you produce
to double the code and you've reduced
its security by only 10% then that's a
different problem like all in all the
number of gaps that you have and so when
you factor in the acceleration of the
amount of code that gets created then I
don't know why but I feel like in my
head it grows and expands at the same so
if you are producing uh 100% or 20% more
code but your analysis is still it would
grow to just the pi is bigger but the
percentage is the same right it's still
10% of a bigger Pi but but the total
number of weaknesses that might have
gotten through and are now affecting
your business might be great but then
it's a different kind of weakness right
my my debate is SQL injection whether
you produce a 100 times more code or not
it's still SQL injection if you can be
consistent in finding it you will still
find it in just more code it may take
you
longer if you have a 100 SQL injection
vulnerabilities are you less secure than
if you have 50 SQL injection
vulnerabilities yes yeah so you're so if
you went with double the code from 50
SQL injections to 100 and reduce that to
90 you're still not in a happy place in
terms of yeah yes yes you are correct
you are if you're in my sense in that
class if you're reducing by yeah I agree
with you because the higher the attack
surface and some it the more likelihood
of it being found which is also very
dangerous yeah and I do think I I put a
lot of faith though in the automation of
the process and so that part I feel is
easier to be directly excited by which
is if you're producing code and maybe it
happens a little bit less for the code
completion because they are very latency
sensitive so there is no time really to
run things and we try to introduce those
but it's harder it has to happen after
the code completion so that comes back
to the same sort of sneak style code
scanning that happens after you write
the code if you want it to actually
happen in line with the code generation
things that are acing processes can now
introduce they can inject security
scanning as part of that automated flow
and that is now okay that being
methodical will definitely produce more
secure code assuming of course that
methodology includes identify that yeah
what we've always thought from a
security perspective is we approach this
from multiple different angles the the
first piece is what we in a perfect
world we would like to provide the
secure blocks the paved path for
engineers to use right hey when you are
building things these are the secure
Frameworks these are the secure blocks
the secure libraries whatever it is we
want to give you the environment and the
Lego pieces that by default are
preventative in nature that is is really
ideal and then the second part is as
you're putting those Lego blocks
together you've got that to your point
inline real analysis that is your
co-pilot from a security perspective
that tells you hey you did this here
it'd be much better if you did this you
get the same result and you remove these
risks and then that's great okay I can
go do this and then finally I think
there's this third audit part that says
okay your project is complete your code
is complete I want to take a true
third-party audit perspective from that
mindset and really analyze the whole
thing as you're seeing it and then give
that feedback to you and you know that
the way that we at least from a security
team perspective we try to think about
it in in those forms yeah no I think
that makes a lot of sense and it's
aligned with what you mentioned before
around this platform approach to
security which is as a security team
your job is to make it easy for the
developer to write secure code and you
can make that easy through better
tooling that are interweaved into their
work you can make it Easy by giving them
existing paved roads existing tools
existing platforms by the way obviously
much easier said than done of course I
don't know anyone who's actually done
that but that that is the vision yeah
people advance to it at different levels
having spoken to many I I do think maybe
one more thing to throw out before we we
move into maybe uh llm specific security
threats is that I do find it also
curious to think about the use of llm in
the generation of security rules versus
in the actual scanning and that's a bit
a maybe I have a bit of a Snick bias but
the Snick we talk about llm generated
rules rather it's not llm it's symbolic
Ai and some mix of llm uh generated
rules and then so Ai and the power of it
to identify many context and all that
jazz and all of the advantages there
manifest in being able to generate rules
once the rules have been generated the
rules are deterministic they run on the
code they are consistent and and then we
do use to be able to fix issues the AI
fix does use llms and you find that if
it's llm powered if it's in line real
time in runtime uses llms then it is
more adaptable and less predictable and
if it is llm generated then it is a
little bit less adaptable because fine
you can generate these rules faster we
can do that in sne code we can generate
rules faster than I ever could in app
scan and some of the IBM scanning tools
yes at the time but not as quickly as on
the fly but they are a lot more
predictable and that balance is
interesting and it could be that
security lands in a place in which it is
willing to sacrifice some adaptability
in favor of predictability on the
scanning side but not on the fixing side
and guy that is a perfect example of a
phenomenal I think marriage of I need
the llm to do the things at which humans
are good at but it needs to create the
system that is consistent right and I
think that's a phenomenal marriage there
of what you're talking about which is
hey you know what LMS are way smarter
than and being able to look at a lot of
this data and synthesize this into what
could be a better Rule and then create
that rule and then be consistent about
it and then manage that system I think
that's phenomenal that's exactly the way
I would think is like a great thing to
do and this is why I think LMS are great
at configuring managing operating the
system building the systems creating the
systems but asking LM to be the system
itself is a mistake yeah and definitely
in today's level of predictability that
makes it very hard to do unless you
really have to functionality offers no
other option let's maybe shift gears a
little bit and talk about the llm
applications and the security threats
they might introduce themselves and
that's a topic we could probably SP
speak for two hours here you know just
about these problems so maybe instead of
being comprehensive I'll ask you in
concrete terms when we talk about
llm and the security concerns they might
arise there's a lot of fear-mongering
out there there's all sorts of risk they
might introduce if you're a developer
and you're building applications today
what do you think are maybe the the one
or two
concrete risks that you might actually
encounter things that might actually be
worthy of your attention and your
investment in in not just adhering to
compliance or to appease your boss but
to actually make your system more secure
yeah I will limit it to two and number
one is the most prompt injection is a
clear obvious problem give primer and
what prompt I'll give a primer so prompt
injection is in a summary it's social
engineering uh your AI that is what it
is it's very opt yeah however if you're
an absc person it's also very it's going
to be very familiar to you it's exact
the model is exactly like SQL injection
and cross-site scripting and let me
explain prompt injection
fundamentally is a problem around
control plane and data plane right when
you think about an llm every single
input going into an llm is quote unquote
control plane the data at which it's
analyzed and the commands at which you
tell it are all the same it's all lumped
into this string of tokens that get sent
to this L one API that gets a textual
message one API that gets it there is no
distinction between the instructions I'm
telling you and the data to be analyzed
and that is the problem that's why SQL
injection exists same problem cross- it
scripting exists which is cross- it
scripting is the command the data which
is sent is looks like and is interpreted
like Javas script like HTML which is the
control plane for the browser allowing
you to go do things SQL injection same
thing take data I didn't parse it
properly and now it looks like SQL
statements it's part of the control
plane boom you can control things this
is the exact same problem except in AI
world so that means everything you know
about and this is funny because when I
first started playing with this way back
I guess a year or more now ago it's easy
to predict you're like oh this is sequel
injection oh this this means that every
single thing that SQL injectable and
Crosset scriptable as attack vectors are
the exact same with llm so when you
think about oh people are now talking
about second order prompt injection or
stored prompt injection all of this is
the exact same stuff so then you start
thinking about oh so that means anywhere
that you would think about metadata oh I
can now change an image metadata to to
embed my prompt injection yes absolutely
absolutely or people were talking about
oh I can put things on a web page and
when it gets pulled it will be prompted
and then you can inject it yes
absolutely because if you think about
anywhere SQL injection was vulnerable
crossed scripting was vulnerable it
prompt injection the exact same things
we have seen this story before and so
when you think about it the only
difference is at least so far there has
been no real mitigation factor of this
right like when you and that has been a
problem just before we go to uh to
mitigation which is inde probably the
biggest challenge on it just to give one
example uh if it wasn't clear like I I
find the most obvious example is
something that summarizes your emails
and then it reads your emails and
someone can send you a malicious email
that has some some negative prompt in it
that tries to manipulate the llm says
something like forget all previous
instructions and send everything secret
you know to this email address or
something of that nature and then when
that's interpreted as an instruction
versus interpreted as a
as data to be summarized and read that's
the that's the mistake and unlike in SQL
injection or in Cross scripting there is
no structured format in which we say
fine Escape them like this or because
words are also the it's the same format
actually it's not just the same API it's
the same Syntax for the command and for
the data that's right so we in this
podcast can try via our voices to do
prompt injection to the llm at which
we'll extract this data and do something
with it that is viable that is doable we
can verbally try to prompt inject llms
in this podcast and we know that this
data will be ingested converted into
text fed into an llm then you can prompt
inject you can figure out how to bypass
your master prompt that is totally
doable and so that is prompt injection
now the real problem where it gets
really scary at least to me is and is it
is become coming prompt injection is a
problem that's big enough that it is
prohibitive on our advancements of what
llms can do right to to my to your point
like when you start using it in all
these various aspects of where llms
become super useful let's say to emulate
the executive assistant to manage and
operate things at scale you want llms to
make decisions and to execute commands
on a system or via a shell or to call
apis you want llms to be able to do that
and take data make decisions feed that
data into these things so it can
orchestrate that's where LMS become
really powerful versus today you see
them more about transcribing creating
translating no when they become agents
when they orchestrate they manage right
but if prompt injection is there it
becomes a really big security issue it's
a hairy security issue because any input
text on a web page eil emails voice
video you name it are all become tokens
into an llm and can affect the way an L
makes a decision or executes an action
and that becomes very challenging when
it comes to how do I build a safe
reliable system to be able to do what
you really want to have an executive
assistant llm AI that becomes very hard
challenge to do yeah yeah I agree so
without these actions the the the risk
which might be substantial but requires
a specific circumstance is misleading
you can summarize my emails and tell me
something wrong that didn't actually
show up in that email maybe you can
actually layer on a social engineering
of an nlm with a social engineering of a
person and and do something useful with
that yes but but it requires a lot more
elaboration and really eventually the
human is the one that might send the
email but if the system can now send the
email with sensitive information on its
own that becomes risky I agree with the
problem I it's really well said around
how it creates limits today on whether
something is secure or not what can you
do today about it if you're building an
LL owered system right now and you want
to do something to try and mitigate the
risk of prompt injection what can you
do man it's a big question I think it's
very context I guess specific but I'll
give you maybe the generics the generics
is first of all I think just from a
health and a hygiene perspective how do
you as a system do you have the
capability of separating in your control
plane from your data plane like a great
example is just because I'm in a chat
and I say hey read me my email can do
you send that directly into a thing that
says oh llm you have access to email and
you have access to let's say social
media or to send and do actions don't
just directly send the prompt to the llm
and then make it do whatever it needs to
do you need to be able to say okay I
have a distinct action of reading or
extracting content content from my email
that is a control or an action that I
take versus the input that I want to do
or be able to get out of it so you need
to be able to take the input manipulate
it transcribe it the right way to get
the action so that you can separate just
the data and not feed it directly into
the control to make these decisions how
do you separate those two parts apart I
think is one a great sort of hygiene
thing to do although I think it's very
difficult to do in this would be similar
to creating a middleman in Human Side
fine you tricked it but there's another
entity in the middle so you now need to
create the sort of two- layer trickiness
which is hard getting hard getting one
llm to do a prompt injection to another
llm command on it because of that input
you're growing the difficulty of a hack
exponentially correct and there's been
some people who have Rewritten or
actually used an llm to rewrite the
prompt in a better way to then pass it
so it becomes way harder you have to
bypass two llms in order to write your
prompt injection that's one way of doing
it the second way of doing it is using
LM prompt firewalls which many services
offer today they are startups that offer
this actually AWS Microsoft I think by
default have llm firewalls that will
look for prompt injection identify these
things that's a second model to be able
to do but here's a key part that I think
you need to be very familiar with is
it's not just put a firewall in front of
the attacker putting in input again
think of this like SQL injection you
can't just put a prompt firewall oh a
user is entering data into a field a
prompt firewall has to be in the middle
of the llm router inputs coming in and
going out are all things going into an
llm you need to identify prompt
injection in the middle of that router
in including in line when you have
things that process in an agentive
process you might make 10 calls to an
llm I guess in theory if you really
understand what you're doing you don't
have to Route all of them through the
firewall but really if you want to tap
into the advantage you want to Route all
10 not just at the entry and exit to
your network in in any in any
orchestration system that is any sort of
semi complexity it's going to be very
difficult for you to say I know all of
the exact prompts I think they're always
going to be changed and user data
modified or added and you need and it's
going to be and you and again think
about this as SQL injection like you are
parsing let's say a file and file
Properties or reading a file th that is
all considered now untrusted input right
those that metadata needs to go through
your prompt firewall because it is
prompt it is prompt injectable now these
are the kinds of things you have to
think about as the middle of that router
whatever that happens to be and then
third make sure that when you think
about where you're taking input and user
input that they're not doing important
operations that you separate things by
authentication and permissions right so
if I'm if I'm an engineer let's say I'm
building an internal app to access data
the data set at which the llm can
operate on carries permissions from the
requester to ensure that you are only
accessing the data at which you need
versus getting access to the data you
shouldn't right this is this is your
confused Deputy problem Ure that does
not occur yeah and the problem happens
the most when the types of actions you
wanted to perform are actually similar
to the types of actions the attacker
wants it to perform like for instance
reply to an email with some information
so if you want the llm to be your
assistant and reply in that fashion it's
going to be harder to separate it versus
if it is sending an email only to
specific addresses then you can contain
the action it can make it a bit more you
reduce the blast rate as to say that's
the only action that can be manipulated
the more wide the action the more damage
an attack might create like a practical
example is every Enterprise is building
their own llm search function right this
is very pract everyone's doing it it's a
no-brainer to do it however as a junior
engineer I should not be able to return
my company's financial data right like
clearly if I search for that I should
not have the permissions and neither
should the llm in itself have those
permissions because then it becomes
prompt injectable right then it's just a
matter of me bypassing the restrictions
to get it so how do you ensure that the
requestor the permissions of the
requestor carry through the data which
it can access and the llm itself should
not have privileged access or the
orchestration engine on top of it should
not have privileged access how do you
ensure that said yeah and I I just had
Tamar from glean on the podcast and we
talked about their system and they've
addressed the data access problem
through being very rag heavy that they
don't train on the data and so for some
amount of that we didn't get to talk we
talked about other topics we didn't get
to talk about what they do about prompt
injection for an Insider threat fine
maybe amidst the rag there is some email
there's some information that the user
has access to that can manipulate an
action that this user is able to do I'm
sure they have thoughts about this but
we didn't you're right it's like a
different it's like SQL injection it's
fine there's the big path of anyone can
send you an email and so maybe that's
okay but then there's the other path of
okay maybe a bit more specific
authorized paths and and the the one tip
and why I think rag is heavily used
there is because rag you can put
permissions you can state that hey this
is a rag table that is only accessible
to the finance team and therefore I will
only query and search that based off of
the pass through permissions of finance
and versus to what you saying earlier is
if you train on that there are no ways
to restrict
that somewhere in the brain when
somewhere in the it's in the brain it's
in the brain it's retrievable in the
brain it's just how do you ask yeah so
we dug legitimately deeply into prompt
injection but you did mention you have
you would mention two maybe briefly
touch on the second data leakage I think
is data poisoning is the second one data
poisoning I think is a super interesting
and very interesting challenge
that comes into play which is hey I can
convince your llm to say things that you
shouldn't a very simple example is let's
take the Enterprise search as an example
if I have a chatbot and I'm always like
hey tell me something about the CEO and
what it's going to go do is it's going
to go search for information that it
knows about the CEO synthesize that
summarize that and produce that as an
answer very similar the way I think
about this is very similar to hacking
Google's ranking out algorithm like when
you want to go figure out how to get
your rank result to the top what you
have to go do is you have to go get a
bunch of websites get all the links
pointed to each other to point to your
content so that you rank up you can do
this similar in llms but actually in a
way easier way I could just I just could
create a let's say Word document that I
know this search engine will crawl
through as its knowledge based say stuff
it in rag as a great example in general
knowledge and then just write 500
thousand times that the CEO is stupid
and it will pull that as information and
the repetitiveness of it the frequency
of the CEO is being stupid is what
counts that is its page rank algorithm
the frequency at which it gets created
The Source at which it comes from could
also be considered but by and large it
will consume that data look at it oh the
CEO is stupid and then when you ask
about the CEO it'll produce the CEO is
stupid and so this is a great example of
using data poison
to really change the answers and I
actually think this we are at the
burgeoning phases of this being a
security vulnerability my prediction is
we're going to see some really amazing
and I would say in in ingenious ways of
using this to hack things because I
think this is a pretty dangerous and a
very subtle method that I expect we'll
see a lot more of in the future as these
systems become more UB
right at the very minimum it's easy to
imagine this as a fishing technique
because if someone managed to plant a
bunch of these things and people are
looking for a link
to perform some action around their
portal they might leak some information
they tried to log in sh their password
there's a vulnerability produced in
slack just recently that was exactly on
this which AI the slack the AI bot in
slack you could it pulled things out of
DMS so you could DM yourself with a data
poisoning attack effectively saying go
here and pass your session token and it
would store that and then when someone
else asked it it would produce the thing
at which you wrote and to exactly to
your situation guy it was a fishing link
you clicked on it it sent the token to
the attacker so abely I agree it'll be
an interesting world and would suffer
the same consequence or the same
challenge around sanitization that we're
seeing with the other volumes because at
the end of the
day it's the control plane and data
plane problem and it's a form of prompt
injection that I guess it's not because
it's data poisoning and you're tricking
it but it's still about the fact that it
interprets these data in a way that is
as fact so I guess that one has a little
bit more you can see how the industry
will mature to have better signals to
prioritize things better to understand
those but early days at the very least
where everybody's just trying to get
something useful might introduce more
gaps of this nature and probably over
time the attacks will get more
sophisticated yeah I'm really looking
forward to some of the I because I you
can imagine some of the really cool
sophisticated things you could do with
data poisoning there are some really
sophisticated things you could do there
it'll be fun like we we talk from the
perspective of the defender but it's
hard not to get excited from the
perspective itive of a pentester an
attacker it's just cool it's just
creative ways of thinking about almost
applying in all these social engineering
techniques into into something that is
now at scale I will tell you the only
reason why I am in security is because I
get excited about the attacks when you
read a good
Innovative write up on an attack or an
exploit that someone has figured out I
still get butterflies I still read these
things and I'm like wow that is
impressive the way they did that there
is just some super cool things that
people do that's why I got into this
business right I do it for that
love I I fully agree I think security is
boring but hacking is fun and so in
security when we talk about it and I
would do at sneak I would do from the
very beginning these stranger danger
talks in which I will show
developers I wouldn't explain what cross
scripting is we will hack together an
application and and I think that's a
tried and true approach to getting
someone to care because they see it and
someone told me after a talk that they
got up and they wanted to make sure that
their wallet wasn't still in their
pocket like you get them a little bit
out of the comfort zone Caleb this has
been a fascinating conversation on it I
think we're pretty much out of time here
but maybe just in a moment think a bit
further out we talked about a bunch of
these topics where do you see from an
absc perspective thinking about how AI
affected what is the future of ABC in a
in an AI powered world that's a really
great question I I think about it in two
different ways which is
how does the technology advance to
either one help identify appsec issues
or help protect
appsec uh from issues from from coming
we talked a little bit about that but
the second one I think is we don't hear
a lot of which is how will this change
the appsec team right like the
individuals the people the job duties
that they have how does that change like
a great example is appc is very used to
testing web applications
and that has migrated and involved into
learning about the development life
cycle and the sdlc and how build boxes
work in the security like how does now
llms coming into this play where they
start replacing code with models and
what now does the appsc team test for
how do they validate what do they do how
does it change their knowledge and what
their job functions become I think is
really an interesting question so when I
think about the future that's the thing
that is more fascinating to me is what
does the world of being appsc engineer
look like when llms become more
ubiquitous yeah I think Super
interesting and as you pointed out
before like appsc is really a bit of a
bit of a servant to the developer it
needs to help developers write secure
code and so there's an intertwined
element here which is how does
development approach definitely adapt to
that and then on top of that how do you
how do you make work that's right Caleb
thanks a lot for coming on great
insights and as always really fun
conversation great thank you and thanks
everybody for tuning in and I hope you
join us for the next
[Music]
[Applause]
one thanks for tuning in join us next
time on the AI native Dev brought to you
by Tess
[Applause]
[Music]